hello my name is green and welcome back
to another hermitcraft episode as you
can see i've started putting this
together now and i would like an opinion
on it and now i know i'm probably going
to be working on this a bit more
but i hope i've got the shape right
before i continue this all the way
around now obviously i've already done
the support beams here and it's hard to
get a good angle on this so that you can
see it but it's essentially got to go up
and
over but it's it doesn't look quite
right yet maybe i've got to fiddle
around
with a few more slabs but from this
angle it looks alright and even from the
ground it looks alright but from close
up
it just doesn't look right so from here
which is arguably one of the more
important angles
it looks just right so the plan is
that we continue this all the way around
and almost seal it off because that way
we have our first layer done and we can
actually think about doing something
with this space
before we continue building the rest of
this giant modern cake as everyone is
calling it
so all in all things are going pretty
well once we get that connected up this
base will be
well we'll have our first layer in there
actually today xai azume avoid
has messaged me saying that he
desperately wants to show me something
and now i've been away for a few days
again because i'm a busy man
and i haven't been able to but today is
the first time i'm going to be able to
so
let's head over to him i haven't
actually been here in a while what is
going on is a multicolored ship there's
piles of sand
whoa
what is going on here is this this must
be exactly where i'm supposed to be as
there's a load of stuff
oh my goodness
is this what he said he said to meet him
at his kelp farm is this what a kelp
farm looks like this is so cool this
looks swish in mumbo's video i was
talking about how i didn't understand oh
what the
what the heck
i was even on the ladder ah
now i've got to go all the way back just
because
i think i've got a thing against beacons
now like officially because
apparently elytra plus ladders means
plummet to one's death what i was going
to say was i never had really understood
beacons but then i started mining just
these blocks here and it was really
quick but then all of a sudden i fell
down this hole uh azuma is down there
waiting for me
this time i'm not going to mess it up
i'm just going to take the long way
there he is hello you saw nothing
you saw i saw nothing you saw nothing i
saw a corpse
well
you saw nothing but have you seen a
bunch of items lying around i dropped
them oh mate i i got here right as they
despawned unfortunately so uh you know
you've got to start over again i had
don't talk nonsense where are they all
right dude so i got i got something to
show you because i was watching a video
with you a mumbo jumbo and you committed
some minecraft blast for me i just i was
just talking about that
brilliant well you'll you're gonna
change your mind um you have a pick with
efficiency five right um yeah this one
yeah it's also got mending and fortune
freon right
now that is fantastic that is exactly
what you want um if i take off my armor
the only thing that i that i'm holding
that has mending is the pick right
efficiency 5
mending all of that stuff
and now you can mine blocks instantly
you can't tell me this isn't amazing
no you just went into creative mode
sorry what this one is
you can't do this in creative mode
that's what's even funnier um creative
mode you can punch a block right but you
can't actually instantly wipe them out
of existence this now here's what you
want to mine
yeah right here's the thing the coal is
gonna drop xp so does the lapis the
diamonds all of that stuff the xp is
enough to constantly replenish your pick
you can make huge holes for free
you're liking it you're having fun now
yeah i gotta take i can see the appeal i
can see the appeal
but at the same time when you find
diamonds then you'll be like oh you find
them really quickly doing this
i guess
that's how that's why beacons are
important
oh my god this is terrifying
what
what happened to me there
what the heck
i'm gonna go back again
why do i insist on trying to fly
everywhere
i'm so lazy i could i thought i was like
in the sky
oh my goodness are you kidding me i've
got to go back again
unbelievable
oh
goodness sake all right i'm back
i think me and beacons have a problem i
tried to fly out of this hole and
because you can't really see when you're
flying through a beacon and i thought i
was being really swish like i thought i
was way up there i was still in this
tunnel apparently
and i don't really i don't really know
what happened this thing is gonna kill
me multiple times
i'm gonna steer clear of beacons for now
i'm clearly not ready to handle this
okay let's just go up the ladder this
time what i was going to say is
the beacon is pretty cool it is really
well it's efficient at mining stuff i
don't really need a lot of cobble or a
big hole but when i do
that's going to be on the agenda to get
for sure
i need to stop dying honestly
a little bit of time has passed
and
i have been working really hard to try
and make this work now i've got a bit of
an issue because i've got two designs
for the top of this and i cannot for the
life of me
decide which one to do i've even asked
several second opinions some people say
the left some people say the right now i
have actually decided
to go for the right hand side which is
bigger
because i feel like it's going to look
like a
more firm base for how tall this is
going to get but part of me is also
saying grew and that's a bad idea this
one will look better but i just don't
know see there's a bit of an issue
because
37 blocks is what we call an awkward
circle
now that means that as you go around in
a circle
there's a little bit here
i'll show you
that sort of cuts across in a very
straight line
and your immediate thought is okay so
you just add a bit here and that's
exactly if you made this with a machine
it would put one of these in but the
problem is if you put these in it looks
really odd and basically it's called an
awkward circle because if it's 100
accurate it looks odd and if you cut
across like this
it also looks odd
so around this sort of mark you do get
these odd little bits that stick out so
i've tried to alter it on both sides
that one is the
straight across edge
and it works
and around this side i actually extended
it out as you can see here i put a few
more blocks in
and
yeah it just it's just it's just
annoying me now because i can't quite
get it right but i think i'm gonna go
with that right hand side there
but that's not what we're going to be
doing entirely today indeed it's another
money-making venture the pickle shop
it didn't it didn't make a lot of cash
cash money i need those diamonds so i
can afford things so i'm going to make a
lazy man's traveling cart and i'm going
to sell whatever i have excess of now i
have spent hours collecting lots of
gravel and lots of sand to the point
where i have many double chests full and
there's no other way to collect sand
other than just grinding it out same
with gravel
so i'm thinking i sell a little bit of
this and i make a bit of money on the
side
not a bad idea if you ask me so in order
to make this little traveling cart i
need to get my hands on a bit more logs
i've got some dark oak and i've got some
spruce but i need a bit more spruce and
what better place to get logs than the
log shop now something happened while i
wasn't recording and boy do i wish i was
essentially what happened was i was
stealing some logs from cub's farm and
he caught me red-handed
so
i rebuilt the entire tree put all the
logs back so nothing was taken and i to
say sorry i helped make this now the
reason i went to cubs farm in the first
place was because this place big logs
inc
sells a stack of logs for two whole
diamonds
i don't got two whole diamonds to spend
on logs that's a rip-off
so i helped cub use his new farm to
undercut big logging corporation and i
built this an axe that goes directly
into the shop itself and
it's called welcome to undercut a
division of concorp now i'm obviously
not part of concorp or convex or any
anything to do with that but i helped
build this
to undercut his prices and all logs are
one diamond per stack so we're actually
going to need a couple of spruce and i'm
gonna go and put a couple of diamonds in
there now so these prices are literally
half of what they're selling in there
and it doesn't look like
they've sold much at all but i tell you
what from the sky
this actually looks really really good
it took a while to get the angles just
right from the sky it actually looks
really cool it looks exactly like
an axe has hit the log shop
and is undercutting
what a pun i mean i mean the pun is
probably the worst kind of humor but i
seem to be full of it with in a pickle
undercut oh it's brilliant so yeah this
has been a really little fun project but
i now have exactly what i need and i
want to put this little traveling cart
bang in the center of the shopping
district if i can to get a good amount
of footfall here actually looks like a
pretty good spot
this could work quite quite nicely i
think we're gonna freestyle this design
because
well it's been a really long time since
i made a horse car of any description
and
i think it's best if we just totally
wing it
the best place to start off of course is
the wheel that should help me out a lot
now making small wheels is actually
fairly difficult because you've got to
use these so if we do we got this is the
smallest circle
that we can make around a single block
then we add one two
and we've got ourselves a bit of a wheel
that works pretty well and we're going
to make this too wide so we want to do
exactly the same on this side i've got a
bit of an audience going on what's going
on
everyone's just here with me what on
earth
they're asking me what it is but i don't
want to tell them so this is pretty much
the smallest wheel
you can make that looks
kind of decent
i'm pretty sure you could make a smaller
wheel with just a single block on a and
a button
but this is the best one you can make
with an actual round shape so we're
going to stick to that for now this
looks a little bit thin at the moment so
[Music]
what
i'm just trying to figure out what
exactly to do
we can thicken this up a little bit
because it is there it's very thin but
if i made it any thicker it might look a
little bit too chunky so i think what
we're going to do is put some trapdoors
here because they're pretty
unobtrusive they'll make it look really
thick without actually making it much
wider than the wheels
this is looking pretty good so far but
it is still missing something
and i'm guessing that's well one that's
missing all the chests and stuff in here
but what we could do to make this work
is make it actually look like an open
cart
if we create a tarpool over the top
this will make the cart seem a bit more
protected a bit more full
and let's not forget that we can
actually place buttons as well buttons
can do a lot but i've actually not got a
lot of places i can put the buttons on
maybe here to make it seem like it's
attached that that works quite well one
of the things i definitely need is a way
up
so i'm thinking we do this clever little
trick if you don't want okay so here's
the thing you can make really chunky
staircases like this
using the normal staircase blocks but it
really kind of blocks the way up you can
make something a little bit more
spacious and airy and less intrusive if
you just use this trick so couple of
carpet steps you got to do a little jump
but then you can get on just fine
these are really really neat because it
doesn't really obscure the vision
towards the cart itself
we need to add in some chests to make it
seem like we've actually got some stock
which is uh obviously a big part of it
the last thing to do of course is to
name this lovely looking cart
to be honest with you i really enjoyed
i've enjoyed making this it's been
fairly pleasant it doesn't really stand
out in any way but
uh it's in a brilliant place people are
going to see it
but we're not done not even close we
need to label this thing for a start so
i've officially called it green's you
lazy sod traveling market buy grindy
blocks
at a cost so the idea here is to sell
things that you have to grind for such
as sand and gravel
and then make a tidy profit of the
people that are lazy on hermitcraft and
just want to buy everything that they
possibly can and i know that there's a
few of them out there so i'm expecting
to make a little bit of cash on this one
the only issue is how
this guy
how can you see me from there i can't
even see him
this guy's been throwing tridents at me
again
honestly this guy's a danger
i'm not sure what quite sparked him to
go after me was it did he think i was in
the water down here
i just i don't know what sets him off i
really don't
because he's left me alone while i've
been building it
i was just standing around here for a
couple of seconds
and he was throwing stuff at me
one way to slightly improve your
building
is to try and make your builds really
fit into their surroundings so one of
the things that i'm going to do for this
build
is just add a little cauldron with a
chair next to it i might actually
change the orientation but it just makes
it look like that there's actually a
traveling merchant here selling stuff
so that way it feels a bit more alive
sometimes builds are about the setting
that they're in and not just looking
good in their own right a good example
is here they only really had to make
this building here for it to be
functional
but what they did was added an entire
pond full of pollution where it used to
be pollution
and then it has loads of dead coral
around
so we're not quite finished yet because
there's one other service
that i want to include in this little
shop but i need to figure out a way to
make it look good
because right now
i'm definitely utilizing this space
pretty
pretty much to the max it's i'm gonna
have to put it behind here i think so i
need to create a quick base really but
hmm
might need a few more
a few more of these i think
i made a two block center which is never
ever a good idea
yep that's probably about what i want i
just need to fix up this crane a little
bit yep it is going to be a crane but
getting angles at this kind of
dimension is pretty difficult
so there's the crane it doesn't look
quite right yet because i need to add a
couple of slabs in here to make it sort
of even out a bit
but the counterweight is going to be
i think here
add the counterbalance there
that looks
kind of attached whoops
yeah that looks pretty good that i might
just change that a little bit but it
doesn't look too bad at all
so it's just meant to be a crane in the
background for a second service that i
want to put in
but what what is this second service
that i've been keeping to myself
why why you suddenly go for me now
oh
is it because it's night time
he can't even reach me anyway
nice try guy
so what this is going to be is a cage
now i'm gonna have to explain this cage
a little bit but not right this second
for a start captain nemo needs to stop
throwing tridents look at this you're
making a mess of my shop
this is a brand new shop this is totally
unwarranted there we are there's a
little cage there this looks pretty good
this has come together really really
nicely i have to admit
the only problem is it's a lot of brown
it's hard to distinguish without any
very nice colors in there but it it kind
of works it definitely could have been
brightened up a little bit but there's
one more thing that we need just to
finish this all off
and then
and the last touch is a drop of coal ore
that really sort of sets in that's like
one of my favorite tricks to use
cauldron with a bit of coal it makes it
look like it's been used and it's just
gone out alternatively i actually
thought about this while i was
collecting it you could also use magma
blocks to make it actually look like
it's smoldering it just doesn't quite
fit in the same way so i'm gonna stick
to the color for now
and now the last thing to do is to
actually you know stock it up with stuff
there we are now you might think this is
a little bit expensive it is one diamond
for two stacks now obviously that
doesn't take too long to get
but the reason that i'm doing this is
because this is the lazy man shop sand
isn't difficult to get so if they're
willing to buy it they can expect to pay
for my time that's all so selling sand
and selling gravel
hopefully this will get me a good few
diamonds and i can keep this stocked up
a-okay and then this is for selling
various odds and sods that i might have
as well as the sand and the gravel so
this is kitted out so i can sell
anything that i want at a premium price
and i also just came across this i've
known about this for a while but it's in
this like unassuming little hut here and
it says do you need an action sequence
well no but i could definitely use
a really cool armor stand so what i'm
going to do is i'm going to get them to
make
an old man sitting
on a cart over there
i've requested a bunch of stuff so i
said i need an armor stand sitting on a
chair needs to look like an old man as
much as possible and it's located at my
traveling cart and also can they fill up
the cart with some items on the shelves
kind of like they've done here this
looks so cool so i'm going to drop that
in
and i'm going to drop six diamonds into
it i think that's probably enough it
says one diamond per stand place so
that's five on the thing and then the
old man itself hopefully that's enough
for it and then hopefully that will
really decorate this rather nicely
so
what is this for you ask
well
why don't we go and find out i've
noticed that on this server there's a
few things that often need
well
testing
so what i thought i would do is offer up
my services
there we go green's guinea pig service
we'll test anything for six diamonds i
don't know if i'm selling myself short
here we can always up the price if we
need to
i guess the last thing to do is to get
inside the cage but i don't want to
leave any dirt scaffolding while i'm
doing it so i've got to delete it as i
go
pop that back on
and there we are
green's guinea pig service
is officially open for business
and now all i've got to do
is wait for a customer
absolutely brilliant this could take a
while i think
hello
does anybody need testing
we'll we'll test anything for six
diamonds
hello
oh
maybe this shop wasn't such a good idea
why did i put myself in a cage
dear oh dear
someone's gonna hire me eventually right
right
right guys
someone's gonna do it right
so
someone
someone's gonna hire me right
okay
i guess that's it
i'm gonna wait here
by myself
in a cage of my own creation
in the middle of spawn
forever